FARHAN

Bekasi, Jawa Barat • +6282298717364 • farhan18042002@gmail.com • https://profile-farhan.vercel.app • https://www.linkedin.com/in/farhan-20241221a/

SUMMARY

Informatics graduate from Bina Sarana Informatics University with experience in website development, both frontend and backend. During college, I participated in the Merdeka Belajar Kampus Merdeka program and worked as a Full Stack Developer. I have a high enthusiasm for learning new things with high initiative and am able to work independently or in a team.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer Laravel, PT Winni Code Garuda Indonesia

Agu 2024 - Okt 2024

 Create a proposal for designing an integrated e-system based on a website and explain the background of the project, the reasons for taking on the project, and determine the timeline for completing the project.

Full Stack Developer, PT Citi Asia Internasional

Agu 2023 - Dec 2023

- Determine the structure of web pages and convert website designs into front-end code to share features on web pages. Directly involved in organizing
- Directing and implementing projects according to the planned schedule.
- Documenting applications that have been developed and collaborating with the Project Management Team, System Analysts, Designers and UI/UX Developers in web application development.

Full Stack Laravel Developer, PT Solusi Tiga Selaras

Agu 2022 - Dec 2022

- Determine the structure of web pages and convert website designs into front-end code to share features on web pages. Directly involved in organizing
- Directing and implementing projects according to the planned schedule.
- Documenting applications that have been developed and collaborating with the Project Management Team, System Analysts, Designers and UI/UX Developers in web application development.

Digital Marketing Intern, PT Bipie

Sep 2018 - Mar 2019

- · Riset Search Engine Optimization
- · Riset product in market place
- Create code SKU and Scrapping Product Data
- · Develop a plan for promotion
- Upload products on social media

SKILLS

- Front-End Development: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Bootstrap, Animate.css
- Back-End Development: PHP, Laravel, Node.js, RESTful APIs
- Version Control: Git, GitHub
- Database: MySQL, MongoDB
- · Tools: npm, Webpack, VS Code
- Other: Agile Methodology, Unit Testing, Debugging

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Informatics graduate

Sep 2020 - Agut 2024

University of Bina Sarana Informatika

 Informatics graduate from Bina Sarana Informatics University with experience in website development, both frontend and backend. During college, I participated in the Merdeka Belajar Kampus Merdeka program and worked as a Full Stack Developer.

Graduate of Computer Network Engineering

Jun 2017 - Jul 2020

SMK 10 November Tambun Selatan

 Graduated from SMK 10 November Tambun Selatan majoring in Computer & Network Engineering. Learn how to install operating system/OS on PC, configure LAN network using proxy, build LAN network, repair hardware & software.

CERTIFICATIONS

- · Kampus Merdeka Certified Internship Fullstack Developer, PT Citi Asia Internasional
- Kampus Merdeka Certified Internship Fullstack Laravel Developer, PT Solusi Tiga Selaras
- Sertifikat Kompetensi Analisis Program Badan Nasional Sertifikasi Profesi
- Belajar Membangun Arsitektur Microservices Dicoding Indonesia
- Menjadi React Web Developer Expert Dicoding Indonesia
- Menjadi Front-End Web Developer Expert Dicoding Indonesia
- The Complete 2023 Web Development Bootcamp Udemy

PROJECTS

Weather Foreacast App

• Developing an application to display the latest earthquake and weather information for major cities in 35 provinces in 3 days, data source BMKG. This application is implemented in the d framework with react.js and local Indonesian api.

Forum Discussion App

 This Discussion Forum application was built with React.js and Javascript. Key features include: Interactive User Interface, Code Security, Task Management, Responsive Design, api data source from dicoding api forum and State Management using redux

Redesign Website Citiasia Smartnation

• Developing a redesign of the Citiasia Smartnation website for a responsive display on all screens. This application is implemented in the d framework with react.js

Portal Berita Indonesia

 Developing an Indonesian news portal application to display the latest information from all news portals in Indonesia. This application is implemented with the react.js framework and local Indonesian api.

TodoList App

 Developing This To-Do List application was built with React.js and TypeScript. Key features include: Interactive User Interface, Code Security, Task Management, Responsive Design and State Management

My Portfolio

Developing This portfolio of websites was built using React.js and TypeScript. Leverages
React.js for a dynamic user interface and TypeScript for more secure and structured code
writing. Stable design ensures optimal viewing across a wide range of devices.